<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qe6j4">
<title>CMV: People over the retirement age (62) should not be allowed to participate in politics.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qe6j4/cmv_people_over_the_retirement_age_62_should_not/</source>
<OP author="deathvevo">
I've noticed that nearly everyone in Washington is extremely old. <claim> I have always thought that that was a bad thing </claim>, because of a few reasons: <logos> 1. if you are already old, then the long-term consequences of your decisions probably won't happen until after you are gone, but will be horrible for all of us that are still around, </logos> <logos> 2. if you are already retired, then you wouldn't know what it is like for a working person today, especially someone struggling to live paycheck-to-paycheck </logos>.

  TL;DR: <claim> old people shouldn't be in politics </claim> <logos> because the consequences of their decisions won't affect them </logos>, <logos> and they don't understand what the circumstances of today are </logos>.

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cn5a8dx" author="Helicase21">
  <claim> Some of your criticisms are definitely valid </claim>. <claim> However, older people often have more varied or extensive life experiences to draw on, and do not generally make decisions in a vacuum </claim>.

  <logos> <pathos> For example, imagine a relatively long (30+ years) period of peace </pathos> </logos>. <logos> <pathos> All of a sudden, war is a possibility </pathos> </logos>. <logos> <pathos> I would like my decision-making body to have at least a few people who might have had prior experience with a war </pathos> </logos>.

<logos> <pathos> Additionally, when you elect someone, like your senator, you're not just electing them, you're also electing their entire staff </pathos> </logos>. <logos> <pathos> The senator might not have direct experience of what it's like to be a working person today, but does that matter as long as they have someone who can explain it to them in such a way that they understand and accept it </pathos> </logos>?
</reply>
<reply id="cn5bd66" author="deathvevo">
  <claim> Although it's highly unlikely that there would be a long period without conflict </claim>, <claim> I can see how something similar could happen </claim>. <claim> However, it's not like the previous generation's knowledge would have disappeared </claim> <logos> there are thousands of guides and essays about every topic </logos>.
</reply>
<reply id="cn5bmo7" author="Helicase21">
  <claim> sure </claim>, <claim> but guides and essays are not necessarily the same as personal experience </claim>.

<claim> I was using that point to support the more general statement that older people often have a breadth and depth of experience that younger people may or may not have </claim>, <claim> and that is useful for decision making in a political context </claim>.
</reply>
<reply id="cn5dcl5" author="deathvevo">
  <claim> I guess we will always need first-hand experience when odd situations come up </claim>.  I'll give you a delta in a bit when I'm on not on mobile.

EDIT: Here it is: &amp;#8710; Merry Christmas
</reply>
</thread>
